(this["webpackJsonpquiz-app-starter"]=this["webpackJsonpquiz-app-starter"]||[]).push([[0],{51:function(e,t,r){e.exports=r(64)},63:function(e,t,r){},64:function(e,t,r){"use strict";r.r(t);var s=r(1),n=r.n(s),o=r(27),a=r.n(o),i=r(68),c=r(0),w=r.n(c),l=r(2),T=r(14),x=r(71),u=r(69),h=r(70),p=r(66),C=r(46),d=(r(57),C.a.initializeApp({apiKey:"AIzaSyA8Zc1aF-8LscY20VAAkgpwnhbiwo2UH3M",authDomain:"auth-quiz-dev.firebaseapp.com",projectId:"auth-quiz-dev",storageBucket:"auth-quiz-dev.appspot.com",messagingSenderId:"221687593494",appId:"1:221687593494:web:dafc1559cd38361d69d337"})),m=d.auth(),f=n.a.createContext();function g(){return Object(s.useContext)(f)}function v(e){var t=e.children,r=Object(s.useState)(),o=Object(T.a)(r,2),a=o[0],i=o[1],c=Object(s.useState)(!1),w=Object(T.a)(c,2),l=w[0],x=w[1];Object(s.useEffect)((function(){return m.onAuthStateChanged((function(e){i(e),x(!1)}))}),[]);var u={currentUser:a,login:function(e,t){return m.signInWithEmailAndPassword(e,t)}};return n.a.createElement(f.Provider,{value:u},!l&&t)}var b=r(12);function y(){var e=Object(s.useRef)(),t=Object(s.useRef)(),r=g().login,o=Object(s.useState)(""),a=Object(T.a)(o,2),i=a[0],c=a[1],C=Object(s.useState)(!1),d=Object(T.a)(C,2),m=d[0],f=d[1],v=Object(b.h)();function y(){return(y=Object(l.a)(w.a.mark((function s(n){return w.a.wrap((function(s){for(;;)switch(s.prev=s.next){case 0:return n.preventDefault(),s.prev=1,c(""),f(!0),s.next=6,r(e.current.value,t.current.value);case 6:v("/"),s.next=12;break;case 9:s.prev=9,s.t0=s.catch(1),c("Failed to log in");case 12:f(!1);case 13:case"end":return s.stop()}}),s,null,[[1,9]])})))).apply(this,arguments)}return n.a.createElement(n.a.Fragment,null,n.a.createElement(x.a,null,n.a.createElement(x.a.Body,null,n.a.createElement("h2",{className:"text-center mb-4"},"Log In"),i&&n.a.createElement(u.a,{variant:"danger"},i),n.a.createElement(h.a,{onSubmit:function(e){return y.apply(this,arguments)}},n.a.createElement(h.a.Group,{id:"emial"},n.a.createElement(h.a.Label,null,"Email"),n.a.createElement(h.a.Control,{type:"email",placeholder:"example@email.com",ref:e,required:!0})),n.a.createElement(h.a.Group,{id:"password"},n.a.createElement(h.a.Label,null,"Password"),n.a.createElement(h.a.Control,{type:"password",placeholder:"password",ref:t,required:!0})),"\xa0 \xa0",n.a.createElement(p.a,{disabled:m,class:"w-100",type:"submit"},"Log In")))))}var q=r(31),O=r(67),k=[],E=0,A=[];function F(){var e=[{questionText:"The correct class of fire extinguisher to be used on a fire with an estinguisher piece of electrical equipment, would be:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"Class A",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Class B",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Class C",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Class D",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"When using a ladder against a wall, it must be placed eith the base out how many feet for every how many feet of rise?",answerOptions:[{answerText:"\xbd foot out for every 3 foot rise",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1 foot out for every 3 foot rise",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"\xbd foot out for every 4 foot rise",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1 foot out for every 4 foot rise",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"The pressure in an oxygen tank cylinder whould not exceed:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"1200 psi",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"2200 psi",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"3200 psi",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"4200 psi",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The pressure in an acetylene tank cylinder whould not exceed:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"150 psi",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"250 psi",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"350 psi",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"450 psi",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"When working on any equipment (or component thereof), with the possiblity of having potential energy sources integral or nearby, what precautions must be taken?",answerOptions:[{answerText:"identify all live energy and potential energy sources pertaining to the equipment",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"isolate all energy sources related to the equipment",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"lock out and tag all electrical energy sources related to the equipment",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"When using pil pumped nitrogen in refridgeration service/installation, what must be considered?",answerOptions:[{answerText:"the use of a manifold gauge set to control nitrogen pressures",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the use of a pressure relief valve",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the use of a pressure regulator between the cylinder and the system",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the use of an apprentice to carry the cylinder",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"When cleaning the water side of a shell and coil type heat exchanger, the appropriate method used is to use:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"inhibited acids",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"acids",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"stell brushes",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"calcium chloride",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:'What device(s) is/are required in a machine room using a refridgerent having an ASHRAE "B" rating?',answerOptions:[{answerText:"oxygen deprivation sensor",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"refrigerant analyzer/monitor",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"access to a self contained breathing apparatus",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:'A refrigerant having an "A2" ASHRAE designation, is said to be:',answerOptions:[{answerText:"non-toxic",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"non-flammable",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"flammable and toxic",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"nan",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"Rooftop air conditioning equipment, according to CSA B-52, shall be what distance from the roof edge:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"6 feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"8 feet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"10 feet",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"12 feet",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Refrigeration system components located within air ducts shall be constructed to withstand temperature of:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"400\xb0F",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"700\xb0F",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"800\xb0F",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"1,000\xb0F",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Combustion equipment may be located within the same machinery room as refrigerent containing equipment, providing:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"combustion air is provided from outside through a sealed duct",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"in the event of a refrigerant leak the combustion process is automatically shutdown",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"you are not permitted to locate combustion equipment within the same machinery room as refrigerant containing equipment",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a & b",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"The maximum field test pressure(s) for a refrigerent ssytem shall be not less than the lower of:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"the high and low side design pressures",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the pressure setting of the high side pressure relief device",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the pressure setting of the low side pressure relief device",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"A refrigerant system considered as a high leakage probability is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"a direct system",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an indirect open spray system",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"one which any refrigerant containing part is located within the air stream",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"The immediate safety concern with all refigerants is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"oxygen deprivation sensortoxicity",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"flammability",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"nan",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"Refrogerants, when exposed to flame, will produce:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"sludge",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"toxic vapours",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"plasma",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"NaCl",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Relief valves are required:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"on all equipment",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"on receivers",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"plasma",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"NaCl",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"The size of the relief valve is based upon:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"system pressure",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"pipe size",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"volume of refrigerent",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"The purpose of the fire valve within an ammonia machinery room, is to:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"put out a fire",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"to release the ammonia from the system in the event of a fire",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"to relieve evaporator pressure in the event of a fire",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"burn off the ammonia",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Fan and drive pulleys or sheaves must be:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"of equal face diameter",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"aligned straight, square and parallel",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"aligned with a straight edge",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"parallel to each other",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Drive belt(s) shall:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"be replaced on a regular basis, regardless of condition",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"be installed with the belt riding on the bottom of the pulley",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"be installed with the belt riding within the pulley",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"be installed with the belt riding flush to the top of the pulley and not riding on the bottom of the pulley",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"When replacing a broken belt on a multigroove pulley or sheave:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"replace the belt with a cogged style belt",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"replace only the worn belts",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"replace all of the belts with a matched set or powerband",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"replace all the belts and drive pulleys",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Compressor/motor coupling alignment:",answerOptions:[{answerText:'must be within .001" runout',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'have a maximum total indicated runout of .001" per inch of coupling diameter',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"have a cold run check performed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"b & c",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"When preforming a shaft alignment with a dial indicator:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"the dial indicator must be zeroed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the dial indicator must be set in the mid position",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"nan",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"first c, then a",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"The amount a motor needs to be risen for a coupling alignment is determined by:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"take a reading at the top of the coupling, take a reading at the bottom of the coupling, the difference is the amount to raise the motor",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"take a reading at the top of the coupling and at the bottom of the coupling, the difference divided by 4 is the amount to raise the motor",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"take a reading at the top of the coupling and at the bottom of the coupling, the difference times two is the amount to raise the motor",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"take a reading at the top of the coupling and at the bottom of the coupling, the difference divided by two is the amount to raise the motor",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:'The correct rod support size for a 2" pipe is:',answerOptions:[{answerText:'3/8" grade 2',isCorrect:!0},{answerText:'3/8" grade 5',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'1/4" grade 2',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'1/4" grade 5',isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:'A 2 pole motor having a motor slip of 150, has a 5" sheave. The fan is required to turn at 2800 rpm, the fan pulley is sized at:',answerOptions:[{answerText:'6.16"',isCorrect:!0},{answerText:'6.43"',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'3.89"',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'4.06"',isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:'The replacement belt for a 1/2" A -38 belt is a: ',answerOptions:[{answerText:"SL - 380 belt",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"SL-400 belt",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"4L - 380 belt",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"4L - 400 belt",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"The instrument used for measuring air flow is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"the anemometer",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the hygrometer",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the hydrometer",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the flowmometer",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The instrument used for measuring humidity is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"the humidor",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the hygrometer",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the hydrometer",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the anemometer",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The instrument used for determining wet bulb depression is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"the psychrometer",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the hygrometer",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the hydrometer",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the dry bulb thermometer",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The method for leak checking an ammonia system is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"a sulphide stick",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"litmus paper",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a halide leak detector",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a &b",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"The acceptable method(s) for leak checking a halogenated fluorocarbon, is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"halide leak detector",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"soap bubbles",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"electronic leak detector",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"b and c",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"Velocity pressure is measured by:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"inserting an impact tube away from the direction of flow",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"subtracting total pressure from static pressure",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"subtracting static pressure from total pressure",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"adding static pressure plus total pressure",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"An ammeter measures current by:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"connecting the meter in series with the load",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"connecting the meter in parallel with the load",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"connecting the meter in series/parallel with the load",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"A volt meter measures voltage by:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"connecting the meter leads in series with the load",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"connecting the meter leads in parallel with the load",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"connecting the meter leads in series/parallel with the load",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"When using a voltmeter to verify no voltage present, the procedure for checking is as follows:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"using fused leads check for voltage at equipment terminal block",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"using fused leads check for voltage at known source, verify voltage present",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"using fused leads check for zero voltage at terminal block",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'"b" then "c" then "b"',isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"When using an ohmmeter ensure that:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"no power is present",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the load is isolated",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the load is not isolated",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a &b",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"The device used for measuring a deep vacuum is the:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"manifold vacuum gauge set",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"electronic thermistor vacuum gauge",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"penbarthy pump gauge",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"meggohmeter",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The micron is equal to:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"1000000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1/100,000 of a meter",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1/1,000,000 of an inch",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1/25,400 of an inch",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"When testing a compressor motor winding, using an wiring isulation tester (meggohmeter), what precaution(s) must be taken?",answerOptions:[{answerText:"compressor in a deep vacuum",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"appropriate voltage setting on megger",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"compressor not in a deep vacuum",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'b and "c"',isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"The number of ohms in a megohm is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"1/1,000,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"100000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1/100,000",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1000000",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"Piping supports shall be a maximum of every:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"6'",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"8'",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"10'",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"12'",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Vibration absorbers:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"are installed at right angles to the source of vibration",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"have the same pressure rating regardless of pipe diameter",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"are fastened at the end closest to the source of vibration",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"are fastened with supports at both ends",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Horizontal refrigerant vapour piping is sloped:",answerOptions:[{answerText:'\xbc" for every 10 ft',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'\xbd" for every 10 ft',isCorrect:!0},{answerText:'\xbe" for every 10 ft',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'I" for every 10 ft',isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Horizontal refrigerant vapour piping is sloped:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"in the direction of flow",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"parallel to the roof line",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"towards the compressor in the discharge line",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"away from the compressor in the suction line",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The type of pipe used for high pressure ammonia is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"ACR copper",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Polypropylene",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Black iron schedule 80",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"High pressure tygon",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The minimum gas velocity in a horizontal refrigeration line is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"400 fpm",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"500 fpm",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"600 fpm",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"700 fpm",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The minimum gas velocity in a gas riser is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"500 fpm",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"800 fpm",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1000 fpm",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"1400 fpm",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The maximum gas velocity in a gas line is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"4000 fpm",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"3000 fpm",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"2500 fpm",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"2000 fpm",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"An expansion loop in a horizontal run is required every:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"50 ft",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"66 ft",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"100 ft",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"120 ft",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The maximum pressure drop in a gas line should not exceed:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"2 psid",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1 psid",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"2\xb0 F equivalent pressure drop",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"1\xb0 F equivalent pressure drop",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Copper piping will expand _______, per 100\xb0F difference",answerOptions:[{answerText:'1 1/8" per 100 feet',isCorrect:!0},{answerText:'1 1/2" per 100 feet',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'1 3/8" per 100 feet',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'1 5/8" per 100 feet',isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The type of tube used for halogenated fluorocarbon refrigerants is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:'type "M" nitrogenized',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'type "K"',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'type "L" nitrogenized',isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"type \"G'",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The Pantone Matching System (PMS) for ACR tubing is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"yellow",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"white",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"blue",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"red",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The PMS for ammonia piping is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"yellow",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"silver/white",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"blue",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"red",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"When penetrating a wall with piping, what is required?",answerOptions:[{answerText:"insulation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"separate holes for discharge and suction lines",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"nothing",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a non-galvanic sleeve",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"When running piping through a public passageway:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"the minimum distance from the floor is 7.5'",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the maximum distance from the floor is 7.5'",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"height doesn't matter",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the pipe must be insulated",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Regarding Refrigeration piping the minimum brazing temperature is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"600\xb0F",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"800\xb0F",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"900\xb0F",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1000\xb0F",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"Moisture on a suction line is the result of:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"inadequate insulation on the suction line",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the suction line temperature is lower than the ambient dewpoint",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the suction line dewpoint is lower than the ambient relative humidity",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a & b",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"A double suction riser is required for:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"oil entrainment at full capacity load",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"oil entrainmost at minimum capacity load",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"to reduce pressure drop in the riser",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"liquid refrigerant entrainment during low capacity load",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"A double discharge line is used with a single compressor:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"to reduce pressure drop in the riser to the condenser above the compressor",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"to ensure no liquid refrigerant retums to compressor head at shutdown",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"when the compressor has capacity control and the condenser is above the compressor",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"when the compressor has capacity control and the condenser is below the compressor",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"To facilitate oil return to a compressor, determine what piping practice is used:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"double risers are used for low load conditions",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"diameter reduction of vertical gas risers",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'base or "p" traps are used',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"Then two evaporators are piped in parallel, with one evaporator above the other, the lead evaporator is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"the lower evaporator",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the upper evaporator",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"neither evaporator",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a & b",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"When using multiple evaporators, having a common suction line, overhead:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"the evaporator pipes are connected to the bottom of the suction line",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the evaporator pipes are connected in the side of the suction line",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the evaporator lines are connected in to the top of the suction line",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the use of inverted traps are not required",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Inverted traps are used to:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"reduce oil migration to an off cycle evaporator",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"minimize liquid refrigerant migration during off cycle",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"allow for inverse flow",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a & b",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:'The branch of a 1/2" x 5/8" x 3/8" tee, is:',answerOptions:[{answerText:'1/2"',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'5/8"',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'1/4"',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'3/8"',isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"An evaporator is located 10' below a condensing unit:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"the suction line remains unchanged",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the horizontal line will need to be smaller in diameter than the riser",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the riser will need to be a smaller diameter than the horizontal line",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the suction line will be need to be oversized",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"A hot gas muffler is installed:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"in a horizontal line",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"in a vertical line",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"in any position",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"to avoid oil trapping",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"Metal oxides are avoided in refrigeration systems:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"a) by purging with nitrogen or an inert gas when brazing",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"by sweeping with air",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"by using oxygen",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Silver Brazing alloy has a flow point of:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"950\xb0F",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1,050\xb0F",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"800\xb0F",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1,450\xb0F",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"A vertical gas riser of 60 feet height, would have how many traps?",answerOptions:[{answerText:"5",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"4",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"3",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"2",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"For question #81, after the first trap. there would be a trap located every how many feet?",answerOptions:[{answerText:"30",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"20",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"15",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"10",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"A horizontal refrigerant line of 60 feet in length, should:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"have vibration eliminated",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'have a "P" trap',isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"have an expansion loop",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"be properly supported with rubber grommets",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"Which of the following materials is not compatible with ammonia?",answerOptions:[{answerText:"black iron",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"aluminium",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"copper",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"stainless steel",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Parallel evaporators when stacked one above the other, the lead evaporator is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"the upper",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the lower",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"does not matter",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the middle evaporator",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Upon completion of brazing a copper to steel connection, you must:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"cool the joint down with ice water",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"remove all excess silver",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"remove all excess flux to avoid corrosion",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"begin flushing with nitrogen",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The ideal location for locating the liquid/moisture indicator is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"after the filter drier before the liquid control valve",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"mid way in the liquid line",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"before the strainer drier",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"at the receiver outlet",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Vibration eliminators should be installed:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"at right angles to the source of vibration",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"parallel to the source of vibration",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"parallel to the crankshaf.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:'"a" & "c"',isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"The preferred mechanical brass forged fatening nut is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"short forged flare",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"long forged flare",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"short forged fpt",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"long forged fpt",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Define orthographic drawing",answerOptions:[{answerText:"3 D drawing, show all sides in perspective 30\xb0/60\xb0",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"shows up to S sides single dimension",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"3D front side proper dimension, sides out of perspective",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"3D drawing showing only important items",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Define oblique drawing",answerOptions:[{answerText:"3 D drawing, show all sides in perspective 30\xb0/60\xb0",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"shows up to S sides single dimension",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"3D front side proper dimension, sides out of perspective",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"3D drawing showing only important items",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Define Isometric drawing",answerOptions:[{answerText:"3 D drawing, show all sides in perspective 30\xb0/60\xb0",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"shows up to S sides single dimension",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"3D front side proper dimension, sides out of perspective",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"3D drawing showing only important items",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The top view of a drawing is also referred as",answerOptions:[{answerText:"arial view",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"plan",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"directional view",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"When compressors are piped in parallel or tandem:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"a suction line equalizing line is required",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an inverted trap is required",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a base trap is required",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a crankcase pressure equalizing line is required",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"The unloading steps for a 6 cylinder compressor are:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"100%, 75%, 50%, 0%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"100%, 66.7%, 33.3%, 0%",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"100%, 75%, 50%, 25%, 0%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"100%, 50%, 0%",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The centrifugal compressor:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"converts static pressure to velocity pressure to static pressure",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"may be subject to refrigerant flow revers al under excessively high discharge pressure conditions",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"may be subject to refrigerant flow reversal under excessively low suction pressure conditions",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"A compressor has a discharge pressure of 250 psig and a suction pressure of 35 psig, the compression ratio is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"5.3 : 1",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"5.0 : 1",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"4.0 : 1",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"6.7 : 1",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The method of capacity control in a centrifugal compressor is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"low side float",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"demand limiting",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"reverse osmosis",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"inlet guide vanes",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"Before a centrifugal chiller compressor may start, what must occur?",answerOptions:[{answerText:"adequate water flow through the condenser",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"adequate water flow through the chiller barrel",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"oil pump motor running",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"Safety heads in compressors are:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"coil spring backed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"used with ring type discharge valves",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"used to protect the compressor from liquid slugging",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"Compressor capacity control:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"keeps the compressor running",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"reduces short cycling",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"increases temperature swings",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a & b",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"Net oil pressure for a compressor is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"oil pump discharge pressure plus sump pressure",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"oil pump discharge pressure plus discharge pressure",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"oil pump discharge pressure less crankcase pressure",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"dis charge pressure less oil pump discharge pressure",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The scroll type of compressor has:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"no valves",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a discharge check valve",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a suction reed valve",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"suction and discharge ring valves",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"If a compressor has cast iron pistons, will it need rings?",answerOptions:[{answerText:"yes, due to thermal expansion",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"no, as it will expand equally with the compressor casting",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"yes, because the aluminum will melt",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"no, because the aluminum will expand at the same rate",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"When a centrifugal chiller surges:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"the low side pressure tries to go into the high side",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the intermediate pressure tries to go into the high side",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"there is a reversal of refrigerant flow",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the bearing radial load becomes excessive",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Which statement is true?",answerOptions:[{answerText:"centrifugal compressors are positive displacement",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"reciprocating compressors are non-positive displacement",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"reciprocating compressors are positive displacement",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"When compressors are stacked one above the other, having common discharge and suction lines:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"the top compressor is the lead",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the bottom compressor is the lead",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"both compressors must be energized at the same time and run congruently",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the lead lag sequence is irrelevant",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"A burned out crankcase heater may result in:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"compressor slugging",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"damaged bearings",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"damaged valves",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"Refrigerant shortage will result in:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"motor over heating",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"poor oil return",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"insufficient cooling",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"Which of the following is not a method of capacity control?",answerOptions:[{answerText:"hot gas bypass, suction line feed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"cylinder unloading",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"hot gas defrost",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"hot gas bypass, evaporator feed",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"A water valve in the makeup line to an evaporative condenser is turned off.",answerOptions:[{answerText:"the compressor fails",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"low suction pressure results",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"low discharge pressure results",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"condenser fan fails",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Pressure testing of a system may be accomplished using:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"air",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"refrigerant",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"oxygen",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"nitrogen",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"Off-cycle refrigerant migration to a compressor may be reduced by:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"pump down",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"inverted traps or loops",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"crankcase beater",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"Compressor oil analysis:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"provides acid levels",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"provides moisture content",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"provides metal particle content",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"Compressor capacity:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"increases with a decrease in suction pressure.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"decreases with a decrease in suction pressure",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"decreases with an increase in suction pressure",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"When the air flow across an evaporator is reduced:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"the refrigerant density is increased",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the refrigerant specific volume is decreased",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the refrigerant density is decreased",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the refrigerant pressure is increased",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:'If the evaporator "fin surface" area is increased and air flow is unchanged:',answerOptions:[{answerText:"the space humidity will increase",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the space humidity will decrease",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the space humidity will be unchanged",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Excessively superheated gas returning to the compressor:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"is normal",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"results in excessive oil return",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"may cause flashing in the compressor sump",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"may cause compressor overheating and failure",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"System efficiencies are based on:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"EER ratios",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"SEER ratios",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Compression ratios",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a & b",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"The EER (energy efficiency ratio)of a 2 \xbd ton air conditioning system and a measured voltage of 240 volts and measured amperage of 12 amps is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"8.4",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"9.4",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"10.4",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"11.4",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"To recycle refrigerant in a system, it requires:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"removal and return to system, unchanged",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"removal, filter, dry, distill oil and return to system",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"removal return to ARI standards and return to system",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"To reclaim refrigerant in a system, it requires:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"Recovery, and return to system unchanged",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Recovery, filter, dry, distill oil and return to system",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Recovery, return to ARI standards and return to 'system",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"None of the above",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"ln a lithium bromide absorption system, the refrigerant is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"lithium bromide",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"ammonia",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"water",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"bromide",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The greatest amount of superheat in a system is found in the:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"evaporator and suction line",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"compressor and discharge line",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"condenser/receiver",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"suction line",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"An internal leak in a reversing valve may be determined by:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"high discharge and suction pressures",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"high discharge and low suction pressures",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"high suction and low discharge pressures",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"low discharge and low suction pressures",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"An excessively low suction pressure will",answerOptions:[{answerText:"cause a compressor to overheat",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"cause very low discharge temperatures",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"cause flashing in the sump",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"increase oil return to the compressor",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"If the evaporator were dirty in a capillary tube system you would expect:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"low suction and high head",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"low suction and low head",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"high suction and high head",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"high suction and low head",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"In order to charge using the superheat method, you require the:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"outside DB and indoor DB",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"outside DB and indoor WB",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"outside WB and indoor DB",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"outside WB and indoor WB",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Non-condensibles are detected in a system by:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"Dalton's law of partial pressures",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"High head pressure and extremely high discharge temperatures",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"High current draw",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"All of the above",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"The liquid recirculating pump in an ammonia system:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"pumps from the evaporator to the generator",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"pumps from the low side receiver to the high side receiver",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"pumps from the low pressure receiver to the evaporator",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"pumps from the receiver to the expansion valve",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"An external equalizing line is used:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"with a TEV and a distributor",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"with a capillary tube",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"with an axv",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"with an epry",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The TXV sensing bulb should be located:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"at the six o'clock position",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"at the twelve o'clock position",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"at the three o'clock position",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"on the suction line before the oil trap",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"The electronic TEV sensing element should be located:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"in the suction line before the trap in direct contact with the refrigerant",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"on the suction line entering the compressor",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"adjacent to the equalizing line",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"at the six o'clock position",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:'The TEV sensing bulb when placed on a line of less than 7/8" diameter should be:',answerOptions:[{answerText:"located at the six o'clock position",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"located so as to not be in contact with oil",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"located at the four o'clock position",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"uninsulated",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The TEV sensing bulb is to be located:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"downstream of the external equalizing line",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"downstream of the oil trap",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"upstream of the external equalizing line",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"upstream of the evaporator",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The capacity of a capillary tube is determined by:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"length and bore",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"pressure",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"temperature",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"diameter",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"A desuperheating valve on a two stage compound system:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"cools 1st stage discharge gas with liquid injection",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"cools 2nd stage discharge gas with liquid injection",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"cools 2nd stage discharge gas with cool vapour",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"cools 1st stage discharge gas with cool vapour",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"A heat exchanger between the liquid & suction line will:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"reduce superheat and reduce subcooling",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"increase superheat and increase subcooling",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"reduce superheat and increase subcooling",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"increase superheat and reduce subcooling",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Hot Gas bypass valves are installed:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"to ensure oil return",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"for capacity control",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"to assist in off cycle defrost",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"to relieve the condenser under high ambient conditions",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"An evaporator pressure regulating valve:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"senses evaporator outlet pressure",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"opens on a rise of inlet pressure",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"prevents too great a pressure to the compressor",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a & b",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"A crankcase pressure regulating valve:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"increases the pressure to the compressor",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"closes on a rise of inlet pressure",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"closes on a rise of outlet pressure",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"is used in conjunction with an epr",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The minimum pressure differential required for a heat pump reversing valve is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"50 psi",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"60 psi",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"75 psi",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"100 psi",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"An abnormally low suction pressure will:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"cause a compressor to overheat",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"cause very low discharge temperatures",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"cause flashing in the sump",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"increase oil return to the compressor",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"The purpose of a gas charged/pressure limiting TEVis:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"to prevent compressor motor overloading",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"to increase the flow of refrigerant to the compressor",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"to maximize evaporator efficiency",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a & b",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"If there is no means of head pressure control on a condenser in a low ambient condition, this may happen:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"low suction pressure resulting from lower head and lower pressure differential across valve",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"increase in conditioned space temperature and relative humidity",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"decrease in space relative humidity and temperature",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a & b",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"The purpose of an eprv, in an ammonia system, with a double setting is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"to maintain two different temperatures",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"to defrost the evaporator in the off cycle",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"to allow flexibility in choice of temperatures",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"to allow slow pull down",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The normal air flow across an air conditioning evaporator is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"450 cfm/ton",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"500 cfm/ton",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"400 cfm/ton",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"600 cfm/ton",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The required air flow across an evaporative condenser is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"1000 cfm/ton",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"800 cfm/ton",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"600 cfm/ton",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"1200 cfm/ton",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The required air flow across a standard air cooled condenser is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"1000 cfm/ton",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"800 cfim/ton",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"600 cfm/ton",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1200 cfm/ton",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The flow rate through a water chiller bundle having a 10\xb0 F delta(T) is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"3.0 gpm/ton",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"2.8 gpm/ton",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"2.4 gpm/ton",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"1.5 gpm/ton",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The weight of one imperial gallon of water is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"10 Ibs",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"8.33 Ibs",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"62.4 lbs",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"12 lbs",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The weight of one U.S. gallon of water is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"10 lbs",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"8.33lbs",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"62.4 Ibs",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"12 lbs",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The required US gpm flow rate through a 300 ton chiller barrel having a 10\xb0F at delta(T) is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"720 gpm",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"280 gpm",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"480 gpm",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"350 gpm",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The quantity of heat absorbed in a chiller bundle with a 10\xb0FAT and 200 US gpm is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"500,000 Btu/hr",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"100,000 Btu/hr",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1,200,00 Btu/hr",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1,000,000 Btu/hr",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"The quantity of heat absorbed in a chiller with a 10\xb0Fdelta(T) and 200 Imperial gpm, is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"100,000 Btu/hr",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1,200,000 Btu/hr",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"600,000 Btu/hr",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1,000,000 Btu/hr",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The water flow rate through a recirculating loop water cooled condenser, having a 10\xb0Fdelta(T) is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"2.4 gpm/ton",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"3.0 gpm/ton",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"2.8 gpm/ton",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1.5 gpm/ton",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The water flow rate through a once through water cooled condenser, is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"2.4 gpm/ton",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"3.0 gpm/ton",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"2.8 gpm/ton",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1.5 gpm/ton",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"A cooling tower will run better in which conditions?",answerOptions:[{answerText:"85\xb0 DB & 65\xb0 WB",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"90\xb0 DB & 60\xb0 WB",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"70\xb0 DB & 66\xb0 WB",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"75\xb0 DB & 70\xb0 WB",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"A valve with 2 inlets and 1 outlet is a:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"mixing valve",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"diverting valve",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"4 way valve",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"band valve",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"A valve with 1 inlet and 2 outlets is a:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"mixing valve",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"diverting valve or bypass valve",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"4 way valve",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"hand valve",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Three way valves are used with chilled water coils to:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"maintain water flow through the chller",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"maintain a constant load on the chiller",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"maintain flow through the coil",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"maintain efficiency",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"As air is cooled, what happens to the supply fan motor current draw?",answerOptions:[{answerText:"air density decreases and current draw goes down",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"air density increases and current draw goes down",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"air density increases and current draw goes up",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"air density increases and no change in current",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Cooling Tower Approach is the temperature difference:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"between the water leaving the tower & the WB Temp of the air entering",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"between the WB temp of the air leaving and WB temp of the air entering",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"between the water leaving and the DB temp of the air entering",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"between the DB temp entering and the DB temp leaving",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The water entering a chiller is 55\xb0 F, the delta(T) is 10\xb0F, the approach is 4\xb0F, calculate the SST",answerOptions:[{answerText:"50\xb0F",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"48\xb0F",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"42\xb0F",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"41\xb0F",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"From the above question, calculate the TD?",answerOptions:[{answerText:"12\xb0F",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"14\xb0F",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"6\xb0F",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"8\xb0F",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Bleed Off:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"is the waste chemical particulate drain in an open condenser water loop",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"must be carefully adjusted and monitored to avoid chemical waste",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"is a means of relieving system pressure",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a & b",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"A variable air volume system:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"maintains a constant air supply to a space",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"maintains a constant supply air temperature to a space",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"varies the air volume to a space",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"b & c",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"Cavitation of a centrifugal water pump is caused by:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"a plugged strainer on the suction side of the pump",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"an oversized impeller",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"too low of a pressure at the pump inlet in a steam condensate return line",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"any of the above",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"The Ph level of water is controlled in a condenser water loop to:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"reduce acid formation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"to minimize alkaline formation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"to control hydrogen ion activity",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"The cooling tower heat exchanger control sensor should be located:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"leaving the evaporator",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"entering the condenser",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"leaving the condenser",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"entering the evaporator",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"An enthalpy control senses:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"relative humidity and wet bulb temperature",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"dry bulb temperature",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"relative humidity and dry bulb temperature",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"relative humidity",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The economizers purpose is to:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"provide fresh air",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"maintain the space temperature without bringing on mechanical cooling",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a & b",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"maintain return air temperature",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Economizer dampers will open:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"on a fall of outdoor enthalpy",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"on a rise of outdoor enthalpy",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"on a fall of COn levels",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"on a fall of space temperature",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"In a pneumatic valve, the throttling range is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"the range between set point and mid point",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the range over which the valve operates",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the difference between set point and differential",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the difference between set point and maximum deviation",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Control range in a temperature control is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"the difference between cut-in and set point",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the difference between cut-out and set point",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the difference between cut-in and cut-out",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the maximum operating differential range",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Pneumatic stats are calibrated with the valve:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"at minimum position",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"at maximum position",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"at maximum position",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"at midrange position",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"The operator of an electric/pneumatic device:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"pneumatic",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"electric",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"electronic",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The controller of an electronic/electric device is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"pneumatic",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"electric",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"electronic",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The operator in a pneumatic/electric device is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"pneumatic",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"electric",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"electronic",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Low voltage wiring:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"may be run in the same conduit as line voltage wiring",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"is not affected by the magnetic field of its surroundings",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"should not be run in the same conduit as line voltage wiring",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"will be of a minimum 16 gauge",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"When two diodes have been placed in series, they will:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"stop the flow of current",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"decrease the flow of current",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"have no affect on the flow of current",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"increase the flow of current to the load",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"A thermistor is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"a thermally sensitive semi-conductor",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"a fixed resistor",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"two dissimilar metals, joined together",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a thermal reactor",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"A positive temperature coefficient thermistor will:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"increase resistance on a fall in temperature",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"decrease resistance on a fall in temperature",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"decrease resistance on a rise in temperature",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"If an electrical phase is lost to a three phase motor:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"voltage goes up",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"voltage goes down",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"current goes up",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"b & c",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"If a phase is lost to a single phase load:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"unit stops",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"current goes up",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"voltage goes up",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"voltage is unchanged",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Three phase power factor is calculated by.:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"volts x amps x 1.73",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"watts & 1.73",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"measured watts / ( volts x amps)",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"measured watts / ( volts \xd7 amps x 1.73)",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"Single phase power factor is measured by:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"volts \xd7 amps",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"measured watts / ( volts x amps)",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"volts \xd7 amps x 1.73",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"watts x1.73",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"To reverse a three phase motor;",answerOptions:[{answerText:"interchange all three leads",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"interchange any two leads",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"change phase A with neutral lead",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"change phase A with ground lead",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"To reverse a CSR motor:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"interchange the start capacitor leads",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"interchange the run capacitor leads",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"interchange the start winding leads",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"change out the capacitor",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Which starter will provide the softest start for a low torque application?",answerOptions:[{answerText:"auto transformer",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"across the line",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"wye-delta",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"primary reactance",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"In an AC circuit, what opposes current flow?",answerOptions:[{answerText:"voltage",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"reactance",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"inductance",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"impedance",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"When measuring voltage in a circuit:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"the leads are placed in parallel to the load",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"safety shield and protective gloves will be worn",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"you will verify the meter operation by checking for voltage at a known source then at measured source then back to the known source",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"If the resistance reading from start to run terminals is 15 ohms, what will be the resistance from common to start?",answerOptions:[{answerText:"3 ohms",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1 ohm",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"12 ohms",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"15 ohms",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"A transformer has a primary voltage of 120 with 200 turns and a secondary voltage of 24 volts, what is the number of turns in the secondary?",answerOptions:[{answerText:"500",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"40",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"120",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"48",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The inrush current of a Wye-Delta start motor compared with an across the line, is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"1",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"0.578",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"1.73",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"0.71",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The basic control circuit consists of:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"control agent, energy source, controller, controlled device",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"controlled device, heat exchanger, controller",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"control agent, controlled device, controller,",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"As the depth of a coil is increased, what will happen?",answerOptions:[{answerText:"space RH increases",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"space RH decreases",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"approach temperature lowers",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"b & c",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"PH level:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"above 7.0 is alkaline",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"below 7.0 is acidic",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"is the measure of Hydrogen Ion activity",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"A blown head gasket in a reciprocating compressor will result in:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"damaged valves",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"unit off on high head pressure",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"fresh oil",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"refrigerant boiling off in the sump",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The oil failure control in the de-energized state will:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"have its safety contacts closed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"have its pressure switch closed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"have its heater energized",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a & b",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"The normally closed lockout or high impedance relay will:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"have its safety contacts in series with the LOR coil",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"have its safety contacts in series with the Compressor contactor or control relay",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"have its coil in parallel with the safety switches",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"b & c",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"The normally open lockout relay:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"acts as a holding relay providing safeties are made",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"is not affected by power interruptions",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"has a high impedance coil",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"has its coil in series with the load",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"A system demonstrates abnormally high suction and abnormally low discharge pressures. What is the problem?",answerOptions:[{answerText:"defective reversing valve",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"defective compressor valves",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"defective internal pressure relief",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"any of the above",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"If the jumper in a 3 wire oil failure control is removed:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"the safeties will not close",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the compressor continues to run on a loss of oil pressure",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the pressure switch will not close",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the heater will remain energized",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Which type of fan is considered non-overloading?",answerOptions:[{answerText:"forward curve",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Propeller type",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Backward inclined",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Axial",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"If the ductwork falls off an air delivery system using a forward curve fan, what could happen?",answerOptions:[{answerText:"no problem as the forward curved fan is non overloading",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"motor overamps and trips the breaker",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"static pressure increases",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"cooling load decreases",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:'A 10" \xd7 20" rectangular duct has a "K\' factor of 0.9 and a velocity of 600 ft/min. Calculate the air flow:',answerOptions:[{answerText:"833 cfm",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1,000 cfm",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"108,000 cfm",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"750 cfm",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"A diode allows electrons to flow:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"from cathode to anode",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"from anode to cathode",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"without any voltage drop",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"in both directions",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The formula for inductive reactance is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"XL=2xPxFxL",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"Xc = 1 / 2xPxFxC",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"nan",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"nan",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The formula for capacitive reactance is",answerOptions:[{answerText:"XL=2xPxFxL",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"Xc = 1 / 2xPxFxC",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"nan",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"nan",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"A decrease in a motors frequency will result in:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"increased speed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"increased horsepower",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"decreased speed",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"leave speed unchanged",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The potential start relay's:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"contacts are normally closed in series with the start winding",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"coil is energized by back emf",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"contacts are in parallel with the start winding",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a & b",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"The terminals 2 and 5 on a potential relay identify the:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"coil",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"normally open contacts",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"normally closed contacts",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"common",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"A current starting relay's contacts are:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"normally closed in series with the run winding",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"normally open in series with the start winding",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"position sensitive",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"b & c",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"Defrost time clock allows for defrost to be initiated by:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"time and temperature",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"time or temperature",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"time only",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"temperature only",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Defrost in a refrigeration system may be terminated by:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"time and temperature",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"temperature",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"pressure",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"any or all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"When two 300 ufd capacitors are wired in series, the result is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"300 ufd",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"600 ufd",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"750 ufd",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"150 ufd",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"When two 300 ufd capacitors are wired in parallel, the result is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"750 ufa",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"150 ufd",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"600 ufd",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"150 ufd",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"When making ice cubes, the condition that would cause clouding is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"air bubbles caused by agitation",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"high mineral concentration",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"excessive water flow",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"excessive harvest time",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"If thermostatic type temperature control loses its charge, what will happen?",answerOptions:[{answerText:"contacts remain closed",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"contacts remain opened",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"no change",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"contacts will default to open or closed",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"Cascade systems are typically found when temperatures are:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"below - 80\xb0 F to - 200\xb0 F",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"below -30\xb0 F to - 80\xb0 F",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"below 0\xb0 F to -30\xb0 F",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"below 40\xb0 F to 0\xb0 F",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Why is the receiver located in the water tank of an evaporative condenser?",answerOptions:[{answerText:"de-superheating of the gas",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"de-superheating of the liquid",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"sub-cooling of the refrigerant liquid",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"sub-cooling of the refrigerant gas",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"A cooling tower with a heat exchanger will have the sensor located",answerOptions:[{answerText:"in the heat exchanger loop entering the condenser",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"in the heat exchanger loop entering the cooling tower",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"in the condenser outlet",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"in the heat exchanger inlet",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"A three phase motor has a power factor of 0.82, a voltage of 575 and a current of 10 amps. Calculate the power:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"1664 watts",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"2882 watts",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"3603 watts",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"8.166 kw",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"The air entering a 100,000 btuh furnace is at 70\xb0F and is heated to 180\xb0 F. The unit name plate says the temperature rise is between 50 to 90\xb0 F. Calculate the cfm:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"842 cfm",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"1029 cfm",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"889 cfm",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"741 cfm",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"For question 236, what should the minimum air flow be?",answerOptions:[{answerText:"842 cfm",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1029 cfm",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"889 cfm",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1852 cfm",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"What would be the maximum flow rate for the above question, to avoid condensation?",answerOptions:[{answerText:"842 cfm",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1852 cfm",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"1029 cfm",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1000 cfm",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Evaporator TD determines:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"The RE of the refrigerated space",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The temperature of the refrigerated space",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"The unloader operation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a &b",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"A potentiometer is a type of:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"two position control",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"thermistor",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"wheatstone bridge",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"digital device",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The purpose of the bleed resistor across a capacitor is to:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"protect the potential relay contacts",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"protect the current relay contacts",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"protect the capacitor",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"enable easy starts",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The cooling anticipator is wired:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"in parallel with the heating stat",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"in series with the heating stat",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"in parallel with the temperature control",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"in series with the temperature control",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The heating anticipator is wired:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"in parallel with the temperature control",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"in series with the temperature control",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"in parallel with the cooling stat",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"does not matter",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Globe valves:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"close against the flow",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"close with the flow",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"are not used in HVAC applications",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"have poor shutoff control",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Flow Coefficient Cy of a valve is determined by:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"the pressure drop across the valve",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the flow through the valve",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"nan",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the quantity of water in gpm that flows through the valve with a pressure  differential of 1 psi",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"A fast response type of control as found across a water coil for freeze protection will have a response time of how many times faster than a normal control?",answerOptions:[{answerText:"the same",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"twice as fast",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"three times as fast",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"four times as fast",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The dew point temperature (DPT) can be read at the intersection if which lines and curves",answerOptions:[{answerText:"WBT and DBT",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"WBT line and RH curve",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"DBT line and the RH curve",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"If the values are known, which of the following will not help you determine the grains of moisture in the air (GR/lb)",answerOptions:[{answerText:"DBT and RH",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"DBT and DPT",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"WBT and DPT",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"WBT and DBT",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"At what point does the evaporation cease at the wet bulb?",answerOptions:[{answerText:"50% RH",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"when GR/lb = WBT",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"when DPT is greater then DBT",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"100% RH",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"A barometric reading is an indication of",answerOptions:[{answerText:"absolute pressure",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"atmospheric pressure",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"gage pressure",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"duct pressure",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"One atmosphere equals",answerOptions:[{answerText:"34 ft of water",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"14.7 psi",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"29.92 in.Hg",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"Standard air is _________ at a pressure of 29.92 in. Hg",answerOptions:[{answerText:"70\xb0F DB. 50%RH",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"70F DB,0% RH",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"70\xb0F saturated air",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"55\xb0F DP",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Discharge air from a heating coil would leave __________ then when it entered the coil",answerOptions:[{answerText:"at a higher RH",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"at a lower DP",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"at a lower RH",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"at a higher DP",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Discharge air from a cooling coil would leave _________ then when it entered the coil",answerOptions:[{answerText:"at a higher WB temperature",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"at a lower relative humidity",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"at a lower specific volume",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"at a higher absolute humidity",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"As conditioned air passes over an evaporator coil, the air's",answerOptions:[{answerText:"specific volume increases",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"enthalpy remains unchanged",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"RH decreases",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"Moisture injected into the air by a steam humidifier raises the air's",answerOptions:[{answerText:"relative humidity",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"specific volume",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"enthalpy",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"An increase in sensible heat will.",answerOptions:[{answerText:"increase RH",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"increase Specific Humidity, increase WB",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"decrease RH DB remain the same",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"increase WB, and decrease RH",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"As the coil bypass factor increases",answerOptions:[{answerText:"the coils efficiency increases",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the coils efficiency decreases",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"the efficiently will only change if the coil temperature changes.",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"nan",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Reducing the fin spacing on a coil will change the bypass factor in what way",answerOptions:[{answerText:"increase the bypass factor",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"decrease the bypass factor",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"nan",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"not effect it",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Humidification would make what change to the heat content of the air stream",answerOptions:[{answerText:"sensible",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"latent",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"latent, and sensible",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"not really effect the heat content",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Specific heat of standard air is",answerOptions:[{answerText:"0.24",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"0.75",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"4.5",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The effective coil temperature can be found by",answerOptions:[{answerText:"subtracting the sensible heat factor from the supply air temperature",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"calculating by dividing the bypass factor by the leaving air temperature",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"drawing a line from the entering air properties straight across to the dew point",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"follow the process line through to the saturation line",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The out door air is 90 degrees F and the return 74 degrees F with 15% outdoor air coming into the space what will the mixture temperature be",answerOptions:[{answerText:"75",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"76.4",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"82",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"87.5",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"What is the maximum tolerance for misalignment for a v-belt?",answerOptions:[{answerText:"1/64 per foot center to center",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"00:45:00",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:".003 per foot center to center",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"1/10 per foot center to center",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"What would the maximum wear be allowed on a v-groove pulley?",answerOptions:[{answerText:"0.015625",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"0.03125",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"0.0625",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"0.003",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The lone tube on a reversing valve is connected to",answerOptions:[{answerText:"discharge of the condenser",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"suction of the compressor",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"discharge of the compressor",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"depend weather the coil fail to heating, or fails to cooling",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"There three tubes together on one side of a reversing valve, the outside left tube is",answerOptions:[{answerText:"connected to the suction of the compressor",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"connected to the outside coil",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"connected to the discharge of the compressor",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"one of the coils",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"The balance point of a heat pump is",answerOptions:[{answerText:"useful to know when you are lifting the unit into place",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the point of time that you should be taking your readings to check the performance of the heat pump",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"when the reversing valve will not switch over",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"the point that it becomes cheaper to heat with the auxiliary heat",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"An air cooled condenser installed in a cold location below the evaporator may not start because:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"head pressure is too low",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"low pressure cutout is keeping unit off",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"refrigerant has migrated to condensing unit",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"b & c",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"Replacement or makeup water for cooling tower is equal to:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"3-5%",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"6- 10%",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"10-20 %",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"20-30 %",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The cooling tower spray nozzles are designed to:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"increase heat exchanger surface area for better heat transfer",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"decrease heat exchanger surface area for less heat transfer",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"aid in washing the air",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"none of the above",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Increased spring tension on an automatic expansion valve AEV, will:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"increase superheat",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"decrease pressure in the evaporator",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"flood the coil at start up",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"flood the coil at the end of the cycle",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"A restricted capillary tube is shortened and cut with a triangular file. The result is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"lower discharge pressure",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"higher suction pressure",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"system charge requires lessening",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"A centrifugal water pump running backwards will:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"continue to pump",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"provide less head",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"draw more amps",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"What will happen to a centrifugal pump if the suction strainer becomes restricted?",answerOptions:[{answerText:"cavitation",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"worn seals",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"a & b",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"nothing",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"The purpose of the aux CWPS contacts are:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"holding contacts for the chilled water pump starter",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"control the condenser water pump starter",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"allow for continuous pump out",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"all of the above",isCorrect:!0}]},{questionText:"The compressor fails mechanically because of liquid refrigerant. The cause is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"CR2 coil is burned out",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"2MC auxiliaries stuck open",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"CnWPS OL open",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"FS TDR coil burned out",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"Costumer complaint of no cooling, the cause is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"compressor not running",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"1MC aux contacts welded open",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"temperature control set too low",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"OFC heater burned out",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"No cooling, what is the cause?",answerOptions:[{answerText:"2nd stage thermostat not closing",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"OFC SC closed",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"TDR 1 not closing",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"LOR coil burned out",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The purpose of FS TDR coil is:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"loss of flow protection",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"momentary loss of flow bypass",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"To maintain pump out",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"To energize transformer",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"The nc LOR contacts will open on:",answerOptions:[{answerText:"loss of system power",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"loss of cooling tower fan motor",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"when PPD closes",isCorrect:!0},{answerText:"when PDR nc contacts open",isCorrect:!1}]},{questionText:"There are how many inductive loads within this circuit?",answerOptions:[{answerText:"15",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"23",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"22",isCorrect:!1},{answerText:"24",isCorrect:!0}]}],t=Object(s.useState)(0),r=Object(T.a)(t,2),o=r[0],a=r[1],i=Object(s.useState)(!1),c=Object(T.a)(i,2),w=c[0],l=c[1],x=Object(s.useState)(0),u=Object(T.a)(x,2),h=u[0],C=u[1],d=Object(b.h)(),m=function(t,r){t?C(h+1):(k[E]=e[o],A[E+=1]=r);var s=o+1;s<e.length?a(s):l(!0)};return n.a.createElement("div",{className:"quiz"},w?n.a.createElement(n.a.Fragment,null,n.a.createElement("div",{className:"score-section"},"You scored ",h," out of ",e.length),n.a.createElement("div",{className:"buttons-wow"},n.a.createElement(O.a,{className:"button-group"},n.a.createElement(p.a,{variant:"primary",size:"lg",active:!0,onClick:function(){return l(!1),C(0),a(0),void(E=0)}},"Restart"),"\xa0 \xa0 \xa0 \xa0 \xa0",n.a.createElement(p.a,{variant:"primary",size:"lg",active:!0,onClick:function(){d("/results")}},"Show Results")))):n.a.createElement(n.a.Fragment,null,n.a.createElement("div",{className:"question-section"},n.a.createElement("div",{className:"question-count"},n.a.createElement("span",null,"Question ",o+1),"/",e.length),n.a.createElement("div",{className:"question-text"},e[o].questionText)),n.a.createElement("div",{className:"answer-section"},n.a.createElement("button",{id:"button1",onClick:function(){return m(e[o].answerOptions[0].isCorrect,0)}},e[o].answerOptions[0].answerText),n.a.createElement("button",{id:"button2",onClick:function(){return m(e[o].answerOptions[1].isCorrect,1)}},e[o].answerOptions[1].answerText),n.a.createElement("button",{id:"button3",onClick:function(){return m(e[o].answerOptions[2].isCorrect,2)}},e[o].answerOptions[2].answerText),n.a.createElement("button",{id:"button4",onClick:function(){return m(e[o].answerOptions[3].isCorrect,3)}},e[o].answerOptions[3].answerText))))}var B=function(){return g().currentUser?n.a.createElement(b.b,null):n.a.createElement(b.a,{to:"/login"})};function W(){var e=Object(b.h)(),t=Object(s.useState)(0),r=Object(T.a)(t,2),o=r[0],a=r[1],i=function(){var t=o+1;t===E?(E=0,e("/")):a(t)};return n.a.createElement(n.a.Fragment,null,n.a.createElement("div",{className:"question-section"},n.a.createElement("div",{className:"question-count"},n.a.createElement("span",null,"Question ",o+1),"/",E),n.a.createElement("div",{className:"question-text"},k[o].questionText)),n.a.createElement("div",{className:"answer-section"},k[o].answerOptions.map((function(e){return e.isCorrect?n.a.createElement("resultsButton",{style:{backgroundColor:"green"}},e.answerText):n.a.createElement("resultsButton",null,e.answerText)})),"\xa0 \xa0"),o===E-1?n.a.createElement(p.a,{class:"mt-1",onClick:function(){return i()}}," Finish "):n.a.createElement(p.a,{class:"mt-1",onClick:function(){return i()}}," Next "))}var D=function(){return n.a.createElement(i.a,{className:"d-flex align-items-center justify-content-center",style:{minHeight:"100vh"}},n.a.createElement("div",{className:"w-100",style:{maxWidth:"400px"}},n.a.createElement(q.a,null,n.a.createElement(v,null,n.a.createElement(b.e,null,n.a.createElement(b.c,{element:n.a.createElement(B,null)},n.a.createElement(b.c,{path:"/",element:n.a.createElement(F,null)}),n.a.createElement(b.c,{path:"/results",element:n.a.createElement(W,null)})),n.a.createElement(b.c,{path:"/login",element:n.a.createElement(y,null)}))))))};r(62),r(63);a.a.render(n.a.createElement(n.a.StrictMode,null,n.a.createElement(D,null)),document.getElementById("root"))}},[[51,1,2]]]);
//# sourceMappingURL=main.e7446545.chunk.js.map